Silence affects everyone in the end.
The Piano is a drama, romance film directed by Jane Campion.
When an arranged marriage brings Ada and her spirited daughter to the wilderness of nineteenth-century New Zealand, she finds herself locked
in a battle of wills with both her controlling husband and a rugged frontiersman to whom she develops a forbidden attraction.
Ada McGrath, played by Holly Hunter.
George Baines, played by Harvey Keitel.
Alisdair Stewart, played by Sam Neill.
Flora McGrath, played by Anna Paquin.
Mana, played by Cliff Curtis.
Aunt Morag, played by Kerry Walker.
The Piano is a 1993 historical romance film written and
directed by New Zealand filmmaker Jane Campion.
It stars Holly Hunter, Harvey Keitel, Sam Neill, and Anna
Paquin (in her first major acting role).
The film focuses on a mute Scottish woman who travels to a remote part of New
Zealand with her young daughter after her arranged marriage to a settler.
The plot has similarities to Jane Mander's 1920 novel, The Story of a
New Zealand River, but also substantial differences.
Campion has cited the novels Wuthering Heights and
The African Queen as inspirations.
An international co-production between Australia and France, The Piano premiered at the 1993 Cannes Film Festival on May 15,
1993, where it won the Palme d'Or, rendering Campion the first female director to achieve that distinction.
It was a commercial success, grossing US$140.2 million
worldwide against its US$7 million budget.
The film was also noted for its crossover appeal beyond the arthouse circuit in
attracting mainstream popularity, largely due to rave reviews and word of mouth.
The Piano earned numerous accolades, including three Academy Awards (for Hunter as Best Actress, Paquin as Best Supporting Actress, and Campion
for Best Original Screenplay), a WGA Award, a Golden Globe Award, three BAFTA Awards, and eleven Australian Film Institute Awards.
The film explores themes of adultery, secret love,
beach, jealousy, love triangle.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.